<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Computational Coffee</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Computational Coffee</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 12:21:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://computationalcoffee.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simulated Annealing</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/simulated-annealing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 12:21:45 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/simulated-annealing/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s a probabilistic technique (metaheuristic) used in local search algorithms for approximating the global optimum of a given function, especially when there is a lot of local optimum. Like every local search techniques, it starts with a possible solution of the problem, but it tries to move to a better point in the solution space probabilistically.
Background The original idea of the simulated annealing was proposed in the 50&amp;rsquo;s while its application in real optimization problems occurred in the 80&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>Must Have Programs for Linux</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/must-have-programs-for-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:39:23 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/must-have-programs-for-linux/</guid><description>Pre-preamble This is a series of articles. I will update this article with the link to the second part when I will release it.
In this part I will cover the following:
Office Suites PDF viewers PDF editors Media/Content Viewers Stay tuned for part 2!
Preamble With the new &amp;ldquo;LTT Challenge&amp;rdquo; videos (you can watch the first one here), Linux-based distributions are now seeing a new media coverage as never before, and, of course, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling happy about this.</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Linear Algebra 1/n</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/introduction-to-linear-algebra-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 19:10:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/introduction-to-linear-algebra-1/</guid><description>Lecture 1 Mentions I think that nowadays in most of the current areas of research in computer science, math is central if you want to do something relevant. Linear Algebra is one of the math knowledge that a computer scientist should have. This article contains the basis of this subject, and what I&amp;rsquo;ll mention is taken from the open course of Linear Algebra by Gilbert Strange, one of the best courses you can find about these concepts.</description></item><item><title>Is Your Password Really That Strong?</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/is-your-password-really-that-strong/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 16:49:55 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/is-your-password-really-that-strong/</guid><description>The latest NordPass &amp;ldquo;most breached password&amp;rdquo; of 2021, is a list of 200 most common passwords directly taken from data breaches and databases of more than 270.000.000 passwords:
123456 123456789 12345 qwerty password These are the first 5, and if they don&amp;rsquo;t surprise you, well, they don&amp;rsquo;t surprise anyone either. Why then everybody use them?
Because they are easy to remember, you would say.
Yes, it has to do with that, but also to the fact that the majority of people surfing the web and using webapps are drawn to do that.</description></item><item><title>First Post</title><link>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 14:50:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://computationalcoffee.github.io/posts/first-post/</guid><description>Computational Coffee Welcome to Computational Coffee, a web blog about Tech, AI and Computational stuff.
Feel free to read and share with friends!
$$\int_{a}^bf&amp;rsquo;(x)dx=f(b)-f(a)$$
Signed, Federico, Lorenzo, Stefano and Michele</description></item></channel></rss>